<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>@mainakdeb</title>
    <link>https://mainakdeb.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on @mainakdeb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mainakdeb.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC - Coding Period Week 1</title>
      <link>https://mainakdeb.github.io/posts/gsoc-coding-period-week-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mainakdeb.github.io/posts/gsoc-coding-period-week-1/</guid>
      <description>This blog post showcases what I did last week and what I plan to do next.
Work Done This Week : 1. JPEG or PNG?   Last week I was able to convert the .tif files from the cell-tracking-challenge dataset into NumPy arrays. The next goal was to save these NumPy arrays as image files.
  Here&amp;rsquo;s where I made a mistake, I saved the images as .jpeg files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC - Community Bonding</title>
      <link>https://mainakdeb.github.io/posts/gsoc-community-bonding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mainakdeb.github.io/posts/gsoc-community-bonding/</guid>
      <description>This blog post summary of what I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this week and what I plan to do in the coming week.
Work Done This Week :   Gave a presentation on the weekly DevoWorm meeting, discussed the goals and deadlines that need to be met in the coming months - link to the slides
  Read some articles/papers suggested by my mentor that deal with working with communities and collaboration, liked one in particular that talks about &amp;ldquo;bursty&amp;rdquo; communication and how it helps remote teams thrive - link</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Next Step - Conditional DCGANs</title>
      <link>https://mainakdeb.github.io/posts/conditional-dcgans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mainakdeb.github.io/posts/conditional-dcgans/</guid>
      <description>GANs can generate real-looking samples, but can they be trained to generate conditioned samples? The answer is yes. This blog post documents my learning experience with Conditional GANs and attempts to explain how I was able to generate images of class-specific handwritten digits. The digits you see above are not real, they are generated using a PyTorch based Conditional DCGAN, I&amp;rsquo;ve prepared a colab notebook, feel free to check it out by clicking the badge below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting With GANs</title>
      <link>https://mainakdeb.github.io/posts/experimenting-with-gans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mainakdeb.github.io/posts/experimenting-with-gans/</guid>
      <description>This gif showcases generated samples from a GAN trained on the MNIST dataset. Link to project repository.
Background : Last saturday, I was browsing YouTube on my phone when the algorithm suggested me a video on GANs by Computerphile. Until that point I had a vague idea of what GANs were, mostly derived from conversations with my brother, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know how they worked.
Anyways, I watched the whole video and was heavily impressed by the whole notion of making computers generate new real-looking data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Did I Create This Blog ?</title>
      <link>https://mainakdeb.github.io/posts/how-did-i-create-this-blog-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mainakdeb.github.io/posts/how-did-i-create-this-blog-/</guid>
      <description>Intro : I should have updated my blog long ago, but here I am, about 7 months late, with a brand new blog. So, how did I create this and host it online on Github Pages, given that I have near zero experience in web-dev?
My brother suggested me to use Hugo for my new blog, I googled &amp;lsquo;Hugo templates&amp;rsquo; and ended up at https://themes.gohugo.io/. I spent around an hour to shortlist and pick a suitable theme.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>